# **Ronald Travis Bare**

Mount Juliet, TN 37122

Phone: 615-881-0624 | Email: travisbare@gmail.com

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ronaldtbare | **Github**: https://github.com/ronaldtbare

Portfolio: https://ronaldtbare.github.io/Portfolio

### SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in Education and life-long dedication to learning. M. Ed Instructional Effectiveness, B.S. Industrial Technology. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Over twenty years of experience in teaching computer/art/technical courses.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git/Github, Node.js, Express, React, some Python, VS Code, MS Office, Linux, MySQL, MongoDB, Adobe Suite, Autodesk Creative Suite, Blender

### **PROJECTS**

# Google Book Search |

**Github:** https://github.com/ronadltbare/booksearch | **Deployment**: https://travisbarebooksearch.herokuapp.com

Summary: MERN stack project to search for books using CRUD operations on a database.

**Responsibilities**: Entire application.

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node

# ServUs Nashville |

**Github:** https://github.com/ronadltbare/project2 | **Deployment**: https://radiant-tor-14793.herokuapp.-com

**Summary**: Volunteer community board.

**Responsibilities**: Database creation and connectivity.

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, MySQL, Node, Heroku

## **Psychic Game** |

 $\textbf{Github:} \ \text{https://github.com/ronad/tbare/Psychic-Game | \textbf{Deployment:}} \ \text{https://ronaldtbare.github.io/}$ 

Psychic-Game

**Summary**: Simple Javascript based game with interesting logic.

**Responsibilities**: Entire Application

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Recent Graduate July 9, 2019

Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp | Nashville, TN

Completed a 24-week full-stack intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS. Certification.

**Instructor** 2010 – 2018

**Art Institute** || Nashville, TN

- · writing lesson plans, administrative tasks
- Media Arts and Animation Department

**Teacher** 2010 – 2012

Metro Nashville Public Schools | Nashville, TN

- Developed the CAD/Design program.
- writing lesson plans, administrative tasks

**Instructor** 1997 – 2010

ITT Technical Institute || Nashville, TN

- Engineering/CAD Department
- In-service presentations

**EDUCATION** 

Master of Education – Instructional Effectiveness
Trevecca University || Nashville, TN

Bachelor of Science – Industrial Technology Berea College || Berea, KY

**18 Graduate Hours – Multimedia and Animation Academy Art University** || San Francisco, CA